Congratulations.
おめでとうございます
You've just implemented a full Kalman filter program for
2Dで歩行者を追跡する 完全なカルマンフィルターを
tracking a pedestrian in 2D.
実装できました
You have used laser measurements to update the 4D state containing the Px,
レーザー測定を使用して Px Py位置とVx Vy速度を含む
Py position, and Vx, Vy velocity.
4D状態を更新しました
But, of course, this model is called sensor fusion.
しかし もちろん このモデルはセンサーフュージョンと呼ばれます
So, we need to be able to fuse data from another sensor
そこで 別のセンサーからの データをフュージョンして
to improve our object tracking.
オブジェクトトラッキングを改善できる必要があります
So next up, we will integrate radar measurements into our Kalman filter.
そこで 次は レーダー測定を カルマンフィルターに統合します
So how will radar data improve our predictions?
レーダーデータは どのように予測を改善するのでしょうか
Although the laser is providing the pedestrian position with high accuracy,
レーザーは歩行者の位置を 高い精度で与えてくれますが
atually, we don't have yet a way to observe directly its speed.
その速度を直接観察する手段は まだありません
That's where radars can help us.
そこでレーダーが役に立ちます
Using the doppler effect,
ドップラー効果を利用して
the radar can directly measure the radial velocity of a moving object.
レーダーは動いている物体の 視線速度を直接測定できます
The radial velocity is the component of velocity moving towards or
視線速度は センサーに近づく またはセンサーから遠ざる速度の
away from the sensor.
成分です
However, we also know that the radar has a lower spatial
ただし ご存じのように レーダーはレーザーセンサーより
resolution than the laser sensors.
空間分解能が低いです
So why not combine both of these sensors together?
では なぜ この両方のセンサーを 組み合わせないのでしょうか
Let's design our Kalman filter to work with new radar information.
新しいレーダー情報を処理する カルマンフィルターを設計しましょう
The state transition function will be exactly what you've
状態遷移関数は LIDARケースで設計したものと
designed in the LIDAR case.
同じものです
We use the same state with four parameters, Px, Py, Vx,
px py vx vyという4つの パラメーター持つ状態と
Vy with the same linear motion model and process noise.
同じ線形モーションモデルおよび プロセスノイズを使用します
However, our new radar sees the world differently.
ただし 新しいレーダーは 世界を違う方法で見ます
Let's have our vehicle here and the pedestrian here.
ここに車があり ここに歩行者がいます
The x axis always points in the vehicle's direction of movement and
x軸は常に 車の進行方向を指し
the y axis points to the left.
y軸は左側を指します
Instead of a 2D pos, the radar can directly measure the object range,
2Dポストの代わりにレーダーは 物体のレンジρ
rho, bearing, phi, and range rate, rho dot.
方位φ レンジレートρドットを直接測定できます
The range, rho, is the radial distance from the origin to our pedestrian.
範囲ρは原点から歩行者までの 半径方向の距離です
So we can always define a ray which extends from the origin to our object
そこで原点から物体の位置まで伸びる 直線を
position.
常に定義できます
The bearing, phi, in this case, is the angle between the ray and x direction.
方位φはこの例では 直線とｘ方向の角度です
And the range rate, rho dot,
レンジレート、ρドットは
also known as the radial velocity, is the velocity along this ray.
視線速度とも呼ばれ、この 直線に沿った速度です
And similar to our motion model,
モーションモデルと同様に
the radar observations are corrupted by a zero-mean random noise, omega.
レーダー観測値は、 ゼロ平均ランダムノイズωによってばらつきます
Considering that the three measurement vector components are not
3つの測定ベクター成分が 相互相関されず
cross-correlated, their radar measurement covariance matrix becomes
レーダー測定の 共分散行列が
a three-by-three diagonal matrix.
3×3の対角行列になったとします
So, our state is still the same and has four parameters, px, py,
状態はまだ同じであり 4つのパラメーターpx py
vx, vy and the measurement vector has three parameters, rho, phi and rho dot.
vx vyと測定ベクターは 3つのパラメーター ρ φ ρドットを持ちます
And the next questing is, what is the measurement function h of x prime,
次の疑問は 予測状態x'を測定空間にマッピングする
that maps the predicted state x prime into the measurement space?
測定関数h(x’)とは 何かということです
And that's how I define the h function,
h関数をどのように定義するかということであり
which basically specifies how the predictive position and
これは基本的に 予測位置と速度を
speed can be related to the object range, bearing, and range rate.
物体のレンジ、方位、 レンジレートに関連付ける方法を指定します
You can find that the derivational disequations below.
派生式は 後で示します
Looking at the lowercase h function, you can see that it is a nonlinear function.
小文字のh関数を見ると これが非線形関数であることがわかります
So comparing to the linear case when using laser data,
レーザーデータを使用するときの 線形関数と比較すると
we don't have a measurement matrix, h, here.
ここでは測定行列hは ありません
And in the next quiz, I would like to check your intuition.
次のクイズでは 皆さんの直感をチェックします